<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?cocoon-process type="xslt"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="/xsl/docbook/ccnmtl/docbook.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>

<book>
<bookinfo>
<title>Functional Specification for the PMT2</title>
<authorgroup>
<author><firstname>Anders</firstname> <surname>Pearson</surname>
</author>
</authorgroup>

<revhistory>
<revision>
    <revnumber>1.1</revnumber>
    <date>2001-06-26</date>
    <authorinitials>anders@columbia.edu</authorinitials>
    <revremark>started writing</revremark>
</revision>
</revhistory>
</bookinfo>
<chapter id="introduction">
<title>Introduction</title>

<para>This document describes the functional specifications for
version 2 of the Project Management Tool.</para>

<para><emphasis>This spec is not, by any stretch of the imagination,
complete.</emphasis> All of the wording will need to be revised several times
before it is finalized. The graphics and layout of the screens is
shown here merely to illustrate the underlying functionality. The
actual look and feel will be developed over time with the input of
graphics designers and iterative user feedback.</para>

<para>This spec does not discuss the algorithms used by the PMT2, which
will be discussed elsewhere. It simply discusses what the user sees
when they interact with the PMT2.
</para>

<para>This spec is primarily concerned with <emphasis>new</emphasis>
functionality. For specifications for the basic functionality of the
PMT2, please see the documentation for version 1 of the PMT.</para>

</chapter>

<chapter id="overview">
<title>Overview</title>

<para>The PMT2 is a web-based collaborative tool for project
management and bug-tracking. Its purpose is to facilitate the
management of CCNMTL projects across multiple physically separate
offices, enforcing basic bug lifecycles and providing managers with a
convenient overview of the progress of their projects.
 </para>

 <para>Version 1 of the PMT (and, to a certain extent, the original
bug-tracking database) implemented the vast majority of the features
necessary for this purpose. However, with testing and user feedback,
it was determined that there were enough requested interface and
architectural changes to warrant a redesign from the ground
up. </para>

 <para>Changes to the PMT for version 2 include a simplified
architecture that removes the concept of "divisions" in the
heierarchy, replacing it with more flexable "tag" based
categorization, a "user-centric" modal interface and numerous
additions to the fields available for bugs, action items, milestones,
and projects.</para>

 </chapter>

 <chapter id="architecture">
 <title>Architectural Changes</title>
 <para>
 Rather than the heirarchy of project/division/milestone/bug|action
item that version 1 of the PMT used, the PMT2 removes the "division"
level, replacing it with a more flexable and powerful "tag" system
for grouping tasks. The new heierarchy will have projects each
consisting of a set of milestones. Each task (action item or bug) will
be associated with a single milestone. In addition, a task may have
one or more tags. These could be things like "video", "content",
or any other grouping. This will then facilitate sorting or searching
of the tasks. Eg, a manager could easily have the PMT2 display only
tasks tagged with a "graphics" tag. The advantage of this new
architecture is that it requires fewer levels of navigation than the
old divisions, allows tasks to be classified with multiple tags
rather than being assigned to a single division, and it allows for a
more chronological, milestone based approach to project management.
 </para>
 </chapter>

  <chapter id="interface">
  <title>Interface Changes</title>
 <para> The PMT2 will feature a radically changed interface
paradigm. It will be focused on the user and strive to provide the
user with only the information and options that are relevant to the
user. When entering the PMT2, the user will login and be presented
with a "homepage" listing tasks that require their attention, either
open tasks that have been assigned to them, or resolved tasks that
they need to verify. From their homepage, they can go to the pages for
the tasks, or for projects that they work on. In either case, they are
only presented with relevant information and options for their
situation. Eg, a user who works on a project as a developer is not
shown the forms for editting project information or adding milestones
when visiting the project page; they see only the lists of existing
milestones and tasks and forms relevant to their position. Similarly,
a manager for the project will see additional forms on task pages for
deleting, converting or reassigning to different milestones. For each
project that a user is associated with, they are considered either a
manager or a developer. If the user is not associated with a given
project, they will be considered a guest and given read-only access to
the project.</para>
</chapter>

<chapter id="misc">
<title>Miscellaneous Changes</title>

<para>
Many additional small changes will also be made. 
</para>

<para>Tasks will be allowed to have their own target dates. If none is
specified, the target date is inherited from the milestone that the
task is attached to.</para>

<para>Tasks will have priorities; they can be marked as "Critical",
"Major", "Normal", "Minor", or "Trivial". The tasks can then be sorted
by the priority in addition to their other fields.</para>

<para>Tasks will be able to have dependencies. A task may have zero or
more other tasks as dependencies. When a task is marked as a
dependency by another, it inherits the priority (if higher than it
currently is) and target date (if sooner than the current) from the
dependant task. Eg, if bug A is entered with a "Critical" priority,
target date of July 1st and depends on bug B being fixed, B's priority
may be bumped up to "Critical", even though it may have previously
only been "Normal", and its target date will be moved to July 1st even
though it may have previously been August 1st. A task with a
dependency won't be able to be marked RESOLVED until the dependency
has been resolved.</para>

<para>Tasks will have a "url" field that will allow the person
entering the task to include a relevant url if applicable and
helpful.</para>

<para>Projects and Milestones will have additional description fields
that will allow the project manager(s) to provide more detailed
information about the project/milestone. The description fields will
accept HTML allowing the manager(s) to include relevant links or
graphics.</para>

</chapter>

<chapter id="non-goals">
<title>Non Goals</title>

<para>The PMT2 is intended as a tool for managing ongoing projects and aiding collaboration; it is not intended as a planning tool. As such, there will be no attempt to add project planning features such as Gantt charts anytime in the near future.</para>

<para>
Requests have been made for the handling of file attachments to tasks. This may come about in a future version but not soon. To implement this properly, an asset management system is needed. Gordie is currently working on an asset management tool and integration is likely once that is completed but not before.
</para>

</chapter>
</book>
