<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?cocoon-process type="xslt"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="/xsl/docbook/ccnmtl/docbook.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>

<book>
<bookinfo>
<title>PMT2 Tutorial</title>
<authorgroup>
<author><firstname>Anders</firstname> <surname>Pearson</surname>
</author>
</authorgroup>

<revhistory>
<revision>
    <revnumber>1.2</revnumber>
    <date>2002-11-21</date>
    <authorinitials>anders@columbia.edu</authorinitials>
    <revremark>fixed typo pointed out by Sherry Mayo</revremark>
</revision>

<revision>
    <revnumber>1.1</revnumber>
    <date>2001-07-17</date>
    <authorinitials>anders@columbia.edu</authorinitials>
    <revremark>started writing</revremark>
</revision>
</revhistory>
</bookinfo>

<chapter id="introduction">
<title>Introduction</title>

<para>The PMT2 is a web-based collaborative tool for project
management and bug-tracking. Its purpose is to facilitate the
management of CCNMTL projects across multiple physically seperate
offices, enforcing basic bug lifecycles and providing managers with a
convenient overview of the progress of their projects.  </para>

<sect1>
<title>What's New: changes and new features</title>
<para>This section contains a brief overview of the new features in the PMT2. The changes themselves are discussed in more detail later on in the tutorial.</para>
 <sect2>
 <title>Architectural Changes</title>
 <para>
 Rather than the hierarchy of project/division/milestone/bug|action
item that version 1 of the PMT used, the PMT2 removes the "division"
level, replacing it with a more flexible and powerful "tag" system
for grouping tasks. The new hierarchy has projects each
consisting of a set of milestones. Each item (an action item or bug) is 
associated with a single milestone. In addition, an item may have
one or more tags. These can be things like "video", "content",
or any other grouping. This facilitates the sorting or searching
of the items. Eg, a manager can easily have the PMT2 display only
items tagged with a "graphics" tag. The advantage of this new
architecture is that it requires fewer levels of navigation than the
old divisions, allows items to be classified with multiple tags
rather than being assigned to a single division, and it allows for a
more chronological, milestone based approach to project management.
 </para>
 </sect2>

  <sect2>
  <title>Interface Changes</title>

 <para> The PMT2 features a radically changed interface paradigm. It
is focused on the user and strives to provide the user with only the
information and options that are relevant to the user at any given
point in time. When entering the PMT2, the user logs in and is
presented with a "homepage" listing tasks that require their
attention, either open tasks that have been assigned to them, or
resolved tasks that they need to verify. From their homepage, they can
go to the pages for the tasks, or for projects that they work on (or
publicly view-able projects).  In either case, they are only presented
with relevant information and options for their situation. Eg, a user
who works on a project as a developer is not shown the forms for
editing project information or adding milestones when visiting the
project page; they see only the lists of existing milestones and tasks
and forms relevant to their position. Similarly, a manager for the
project will see additional forms on task pages for deleting,
converting or reassigning to different milestones. For each project
that a user is associated with, they are considered either a manager,
a developer, or a guest. If the user is not associated with a given
project and that project is publicly view-able, they will be considered
a guest and given read-only access to the project. Guests can still
submit bug reports on a project, but the ownership of the bug is
transferred to the project caretaker.</para>

</sect2>

<sect2>
<title>Miscellaneous Changes</title>
<para>
Many additional small changes have also be made. 
</para>

<para>Tasks will are allowed to have their own target dates. If none is
specified, the target date is inherited from the milestone that the
task is attached to.</para>

<para>Tasks have priorities; There are 5 levels of priorities, 0 - 4,
where 4 is the highest priority. The tasks can then be sorted by the
priority in addition to their other fields.</para>

<para>Tasks also have dependencies. A task may have zero or
more other tasks as dependencies. When a task is marked as a
dependency by another, it inherits the priority (if higher than it
currently is) and target date (if sooner than the current) from the
dependent task. Eg, if bug A is entered with a "4" priority,
target date of July 1st and depends on bug B being fixed, B's priority
may be bumped up to "4", even though it may have previously
only been "2", and its target date will be moved to July 1st even
though it may have previously been August 1st. A task with a
dependency won't be able to be marked RESOLVED until the dependency
has been resolved.</para>

<para>Tasks have a "url" field that allows the person entering the
task to include a relevant url if applicable and helpful.</para>

<para>Projects and Milestones have additional description fields
that allow the project manager(s) to provide more detailed
information about the project/milestone. The description fields 
accept HTML, allowing the manager(s) to include relevant links or
graphics.</para>

<para>An Experimental calendar mode has been added that allows project
target dates to be viewed in a calendar layout. </para>

<para>Time tracking has been added. Each task has an estimated time
that is assigned when the item is created (and can be edited later).
When an item is resolved, the developer resolving the task is provided with
a field to enter the actual time that it took to resolve the task. These
fields are then used to calculate various metrics for users and projects. Eg, 
on a user's page the total estimated time for open tasks assigned to them is listed, 
for milestones, the estimated remaining time and the total time already
put into the milestone is listed.</para>

<para>There is now a concept of "groups" of users. Eg, "part-timers"
can be treated as a group. Entire groups can easily be added to projects and,
if it isn't very important who completes a task, it can be assigned to a group
rather than an individual. Then, someone in the group can claim the task.</para>

<para>The PMT also now includes project forums and personal logs. This is a 
basic threaded discussion board. For each project in the PMT, there is a project
forum where developers can discuss the project. The forums are tied into
email so that if a post is made to the forum, all members of the project team 
are emailed. There are also individual personal logs which can serve as a sort
of professional diary. The individual logs are an excellent place to talk
about things you are working on that aren't directly covered by the PMT.</para>

</sect2>


</sect1>
</chapter>

<chapter id="quickstart">
<title>PMT2 Quickstart</title>
<procedure>

<step> <para>First, you must create a user account for yourself. Go to
<ulink
href="http://www2.ccnmtl.columbia.edu/pmt2/">http://www2.ccnmtl.columbia.edu/pmt2/</ulink>. </para>
</step>

<step><para> Follow the <ulink
href="http://www2.ccnmtl.columbia.edu/pmt2/add_user.pl">create a new
user account</ulink> link. </para></step> <step><para>You will be
presented with a form asking for your desired username, password (and
verification), full name, and email address. Enter the information
that it asks for. Your username is a short identifier that you will
use to login to the system. Your email address will be used to notify
you when items are assigned to you, or otherwise require your
attention. Please enter your full email address, not just your CUNI
(eg, enter <userinput>abc1@columbia.edu</userinput> and not just
<userinput>abc1</userinput>. it is important that you enter a valid
email address. if it is invalid, anders will be forced to hunt you
down and make you fix it.<caution>Username and password fields are
case sensitive. <userinput>foo</userinput> is not equivalent to
<userinput>FoO</userinput>.</caution></para></step>

<step><para>Once the system has accepted your information, it will
present you with a <ulink
href="http://www2.ccnmtl.columbia.edu/pmt2/login.pl">login
screen</ulink>. Use the username and password that you just created to
log in.</para></step>

<step><para>At this point, you should be presented with your <ulink
href="http://www2.ccnmtl.columbia.edu/pmt2/home.pl">homepage</ulink>. Your
homepage shows a list of all items which require your attention sorted
by priority by default (you can sort on any other attribute as
well). Since your account has just been created, you probably haven't
been added to any projects yet and don't have any items assigned to
you, so this page will be mostly blank except for a small form for
changing your user info (enjoy it while it lasts. once you get added to projects and people
start assigning things to you, you'll long for a nice blank homepage). 
Since only managers for projects can add users
to their projects, one of the first things you should do is contact
any managers for projects you work on letting them know that you
should be added to their project entries.</para>

<para>At the top of the homepage, (and every other page as long as you're logged in) is the menubar. The menubar allows you to quickly navigate the PMT and access its functionality. Here is a description of the parts of the menubar:</para>

<para><graphic width='700' depth='103' fileref='menubar.png'/></para>
<orderedlist>
<listitem><para>This is a link back to your homepage.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Logout button. Click when you're done using the PMT. If you are on your own private machine, there is probably no reason to logout, but if you are on a lab, or other public machine, you probably don't want to leave your account logged in.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>This is a link to this tutorial</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Link to the searching and filtering interface. </para></listitem>
<listitem><para>This menu item allows you to add a bug or action item to any project that you are associated with or is publicly viewable. Select the type (bug or action item) and the project with the two menus and hit 'go'.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>This pulldown menu will take you to any project that you are associated with (IE, you are a manager, developer, or guest on the project). It will also allow you to go to the page for creating a new project.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>This pulldown allows you to jump directly to any of the publicly viewable projects that you are not associated with. </para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Visit the projects forum or post to the forum.</para></listitem>
</orderedlist>

</step>



<step><para>You can also, if you wish, create your own projects. The
menu at the top of your user page (and every other page in the PMT)
contains a pulldown labeled "goto project:". The last entry in this
pulldown is "create new project". When you select this one, it will
take you to a form for creating a new project entry. The form asks for
project name, description, final release date, and whether the project
is public or private. The description field will accept HTML, so you
can include things like links to the project itself and/or
documentation. The final release date is the date that you expect the
project to be completed by; This can be changed at any point in the
future, so don't worry if you haven't yet figured out the project
schedule in that great of detail. The view field determines whether
the project is viewable by people not explicitly associated with it
(managers, developers, and guests). You can, for example, create your
own private project to use as a web-based todo list and no one else
will be able to view it. Again, all of these fields can be changed at
any point, so there's no need to agonize over them. When you create a
project, it automatically creates a "Final Release" milestone with the
target date specified, and identifies you as a manager for the project
(and as the project 'caretaker').</para></step>

<step><para>Once you've been added to (or created your own) a project,
it will appear in the "goto project:" and "add bug/action item to
project" pulldowns in the menu so that you can either jump directly to
or add an item to any project you are affiliated with at any point. On
the left of the menu, next to the CCNMTL logo, will be your username
with a link to your homepage. Next to that is a link for logging
out. It is advised that you log out after using the PMT from a public,
or lab, machine.</para></step>

<step><para>Now, you should acquaint yourself with the rest of the PMT
by reading the rest of the tutorial as you explore its
functionality. It is advised that you create a private test project now to
experiment on and get a feel for how the system works.</para></step>

</procedure>
</chapter>

<chapter id="theory">
<title>Theory: A Method to the Madness</title>
<sect1><title>Lifecycles</title>

<para>Strict bug-tracking is vital to a large project. Most people
have a very limited short term memory when it comes to remembering
what bugs they have that need to be fixed. Bugs also have a way of
resurfacing in software projects in particular. New code may
inadvertently re-break old bugs which were previously thought to be
fixed.</para>

<procedure>

<step><para>If a bug or action item is entered into the PMT by a user
who is affiliated with the project (either as a manager, developer, or
guest), it is assigned to the designated user and given a status of
'OPEN'. The user who entered the item is considered its "owner". If
the item is entered by someone outside the project, it is created with
a status of 'UNASSIGNED' and is both assigned to (temporarily) and
owned by the project's 'caretaker', whose responsibility it is to
assign the item to the proper user.</para></step>

<step><para>The user to whom the item has been assigned fixes the bug,
completes the action item, or otherwise deals with the item and sets
the status to "RESOLVED" with a resolved-status of
"FIXED","INVALID","WONTFIX","DUPLICATE", or "WORKSFORME" as explained
below.</para></step>

<step><para>Optionally, the item may be marked as 'IN PROGRESS',
signifying that the item is currently being worked on but has not been
completed yet.</para></step>

<step><para>After it is resolved, the item is passed back to the owner
who checks to see if the item has been satisfactorily resolved. If it
is now fixed or completed, the owner sets the status to
"VERIFIED". Otherwise, the owner reopens the item by setting the
status to "REOPENED", providing a brief explanation of why it is being
reopened, and, if necessary, reassigns the item to another user. The
process then returns to step 2.  </para></step>

<step><para>When a milestone is reached, all items assigned to it that
were marked as 'VERIFIED' are changed to 'CLOSED'.</para></step>
</procedure>

<para>The following diagram shows the possible state transitions for items in the PMT2:</para>

<para><graphic width='495' depth='529' fileref='pmt2_bug_lifecycle.png'/></para>

</sect1>
</chapter>

<chapter id="accounts">
<title>User Accounts</title>
<sect1><title>Creating a new user account</title></sect1>
<para>See the "Quickstart" section.</para>
<sect1><title>Your "home" page</title></sect1>

<para>Your homepage is an attempt to aggregate the most information
most relevant to a particular user in one place. It focuses on a list
of items that, in one way or another, are of interest to that
user. This includes items that have been assigned to the user and are
in an OPEN state (meaning that the user must either complete this
action item or fix this bug), and items that are owned by the user
that have been resolved (meaning that they must be verified by the
user). The items are arranged in a table and may be sorted by title,
priority, target date, status, project, or last modified time (they
are sorted in descending order of priority by default) by clicking on
the corresponding header. For users who are developers in particular,
this page will be the primary (and most useful) interface to the PMT
and can be a very useful aide in scheduling ones time.</para>

<sect1><title>Editing user info</title>

<para>At the bottom of your homepage is a form allowing you to change
your user info (full name, email) or change your password.</para>

</sect1>
<sect1><title>Forget your password?</title>

<para>There is a form at the bottom of the login page that will allow
you to receive an email reminder of your password. Just enter your
username in the form and hit the submit button. Your password will be
mailed to the email address that you specified when your account was
created.</para>

</sect1>
</chapter>

<chapter id="items">
<title>Bugs and Action Items</title>
<sect1><title>What's the difference?</title></sect1>

<para>A bug is simply a problem with a product. Either something is
there that shouldn't be there or something that should be there
isn't. Action items are merely tasks assigned to a developer.</para>

<sect1><title>Locating and viewing</title>

<para>You can view a bug/action item by entering its ID number into
the box on the very right of the menu and hitting "go". Alternatively,
you can reach the bug by going to the appropriate project page and
following the link to it, or by following a link from your homepage,
etc.</para>

<sect2><title>Parts of an Item</title>
<variablelist>
<varlistentry><term>Title</term>
<listitem>
<para>
The title of the item. Should be concise and meaningful.
</para>
</listitem>
</varlistentry>

<varlistentry><term>Type</term>
<listitem>
<para>
Bug or Action Item. Only managers can convert between the types.
</para>
</listitem>
</varlistentry>

<varlistentry><term>ID</term>
<listitem>
<para>
A unique ID. Every item in the PMT has its own. You can quickly reach
any item whose ID you know with the form on the right of the menubar.
</para>
</listitem>
</varlistentry>

<varlistentry><term>Project</term>
<listitem>
<para>
The project which the item is associated with. This field cannot be changed.
</para>
</listitem>
</varlistentry>

<varlistentry><term>Milestone</term>
<listitem>
<para>
The milestone to which the item is assigned. Only the managers of the project can reassign bugs to different milestones.
</para>
</listitem>
</varlistentry>

<varlistentry><term>STATUS</term>
<listitem>
<para>
The current status of the item. May be UNASSIGNED, OPEN, RESOLVED, VERIFIED, or CLOSED. See the lifecycle section for more information on this field.
</para>
</listitem>
</varlistentry>

<varlistentry><term>Priority</term>
<listitem>
<para>
The urgency with which the item must be handled. Ranges from 0-4 with 4 being the highest priority. Numbers were used for priority instead of text designations such as "blocker", "critical", "important", etc. to avoid ambiguity and to allow project managers to use whatever system they like on a project by project basis.
</para>
</listitem>
</varlistentry>

<varlistentry><term>Target Date</term>
<listitem>
<para>
The date by which the item should be completed. If this date isn't specified when the item is created, it is inherited from the milestone that it is assigned to.
</para>
</listitem>
</varlistentry>

<varlistentry><term>Assigned To</term>
<listitem>
<para>
The user responsible for the item. One way or another, this user is expected to resolve the item, either by fixing the bug, completing the action item, or resolving with some other appropriate conditional such as "WONTFIX", "DUPLICATE", "INVALID", etc. 
</para>
</listitem>
</varlistentry>

<varlistentry><term>Owner</term>
<listitem>
<para>
The user who entered the item (usually) and who is responsible for verifying the item once it has been marked as resolved.
</para>
</listitem>
</varlistentry>

<varlistentry><term>last modified</term>
<listitem>
<para>
The date and time of the last modification to the item. Includes actions such as status changes, edits, or comments being attached.
</para>
</listitem>
</varlistentry>

<varlistentry><term>Tags</term>
<listitem>
<para>
A fairly free-form way of classifying and grouping items. Any item can have zero or more tags associated with it. A user can then filter the list of items in a project by tag, showing only items that have been tagged with that tag.
</para>
</listitem>
</varlistentry>

<varlistentry><term>Dependencies</term>
<listitem>
<para>
Any other items that must be resolved before this item can be resolved. Eg, perhaps an item related to project integration cannot be completed until all of the components such as content, design, and video, have been completed. All dependencies inherit the priority and target date from the item (if it is higher or closer, respectively).
</para>
</listitem>
</varlistentry>


<varlistentry><term>Dependents</term>
<listitem>
<para>
The inverse of Dependencies. These are the items which depend on this item being completed.
</para>
</listitem>
</varlistentry>

<varlistentry><term>Description</term>
<listitem>
<para>
A clear description of the bug or action item. Normally one or two paragraphs. For a bug report, it should cover steps for the developer to reproduce the bug and include any relevant information such as platform or release version.
</para>
</listitem>
</varlistentry>

<varlistentry><term>Estimated Time</term>
<listitem>
<para>
The amount of time it will take to complete the bug or action item.
Ideally, this should be discussed and agreed upon before the action item
is entered. However, this often doesn't happen, so the estimated time can
be editted after the item is added. 
</para>
</listitem>
</varlistentry>

</variablelist>
</sect2>

</sect1>
<sect1><title>updating/editing</title>

<para>If you have the appropriate access (IE, you are a manager or
developer on a project) there will be a link at the top of an item
page that will take you to a form for editing the attributes of the
item. Managers and developers are presented with slightly different
forms; managers have the ability to delete the item, change its type
(bug to action item and vice versa), and change the milestone that
it's attached to. Any number of the editable fields may be changed at
one time. The system will detect which fields have been changed and
add the appropriate event to the item's history (see below).</para>

</sect1>
<sect1><title>email notification</title>

<para>One of the new features in the PMT2 is increased control over
email notification. For any item, a user may opt to be notified by
email whenever that item is updated. When an item is created, the user
it is assigned to, the item's owner and all managers in the project
are added to the list of users to be notified on updates for that
item. </para>

<para>Anyone may add themselves to this list, or remove themselves
from the list. When visiting the item page, there will be a link at
the top that says either "notify me when this [bug/action item] is
updated" or "do not notify me when this [bug/action item] is updated"
depending on whether you are on the notify list or not. clicking on
this link will change your status in the expected manner.</para>

</sect1>
<sect1><title>history</title>

<para> A chronological list of changes made to the item. Begins with
the creation of the item. Includes the status and a description of the
changes made for each event along with any comments added by the user
making the change.  </para>

</sect1>
<sect1><title>comments</title>

<para> Any comments made by users about the item. Serves as a minimal
discussion, whiteboard area allowing for basic conversation about the
item.  </para>

</sect1>

<sect1><title>actual times</title>
<para>When an task is resolved (specifically, when it is resolved as FIXED), 
the developer resolving the task should enter the actual time that it took
to complete the task. This helps the Center get a better idea of how
resources are being allocated on projects and make better predictions
for the future. Since a task may potentially be re-opened and re-resolved multiple
times, potentially by multiple people, the PMT keeps track of the individual
resolution times and who entered them.</para>
</sect1>

</chapter>

<chapter id="projects">
<title>Projects and Project Management</title>
<sect1><title>Creating a new project entry</title>

<para>Select the "create new project" entry from the projects pulldown
menu. See the quickstart section for more info.</para>

</sect1>

<sect1><title>Classes of users</title>

<para>There are 3 groups of users in any given project: managers,
developers, and guests. </para>

<para> Guests are primarily useful if you have a project entry that is
marked as private; then you can add people who aren't actually working
on the project but that you'd like to have access to it as
'guests'. They can view the project, add comments, and assign things
to other people but you can't assign anything to them. If a project
entry is marked as 'public', essentially everyone else with a pmt
account is considered a guest of the project (kindof).</para>

<para>Developers are the "normal" class of people on a project. It
would include programmers, testers, content people, etc. They're the
ones who do the work. You can assign things to them and they can
assign things to other people.</para>

<para>Managers are basically like the developers but they also have
some more power over the administrative stuff: they can add and remove
users from the project and change milestone stuff. Also, managers are
by default included on all of the email; the idea is that managers
like to always know what's going on with a project. So if developer A
assigns something to developer B, all the managers also get the email
notification. If a milestone is missed, the developer(s) holding up
the milestone and the managers all get the email reminders.</para>

<para>The "caretaker" is one special user who's primary responsibility
as caretaker is to assign items that come in from the outside. Eg, if
there are 5 developers working on a project and a user wants to report
a bug but has no idea who's working on what part and who they should
assign it to, they assign it to "caretaker". The caretaker user then
should look at it, figure out who it belongs to and reassign it to
them. By default, the user who creates the project entry in the PMT is
made the caretaker.</para>


</sect1>

<sect1><title>Editing a project entry</title>

<para>Only managers of a project may edit the project data. Clicking
the "edit project data" link at the top of the project page will allow
managers to edit the title of the project, the description, the
caretaker, add and remove managers, developers, and guests, add
milestones and delete the project entry.</para>

</sect1>
<sect1><title>Milestones</title></sect1>

<para>A milestone is simply a progress marker for a project. They
allow the manager(s) to accurately gauge the progress and help make
decisions about scheduling and feature inclusion/removal.</para>

<para>Each milestone for a project has a name, a target date to meet,
 and a status. Action items and
bugs are assigned to a milestone and must be resolved before that
milestone is considered met (or reassigned to a later milestone).
</para>
<sect2><title>Milestone Lifecycle</title>
<procedure>

<step><para>When a milestone is added to a project, its status is
'OPEN'. As long as any of the items assigned to the milestone are in
the 'OPEN', 'UNASSIGNED', or 'IN PROGRESS', the milestone will remain
'OPEN'.</para></step>

<step><para>Whenever the status of an item is changed, its milestone
is re-evaluated. If it no longer has any open items, the milestone
will become 'CLOSED'.</para></step>

<step><para>If a new (and OPEN) item is added to the milestone or an
item on the milestone is reopened, the milestone will also become
reopened.</para></step>

<step><para>The system provides email reminders about open
milestones. One week before the milestone's target date, one day
before and every day afterwords that the milestone remains open, all
managers and developers on the project will receive email reminders of
its open status. These reminders will stop as soon as the milestone is
closed.</para></step>

</procedure>
</sect2>
</chapter>

<chapter id="forums">
<title>Forums</title>
<para>The PMT now includes a basic, easy to use threaded discussion board
for internal project related discussion.</para>

<para>In the menubar at the top of every page is a link to the 
forums page. This general page shows an overview of all the forums
that are active for the projects along with log entries and a quick
listing of the most recently modified items. Posts are displayed in
descending order of when they were posted or when a reply was posted.
This page provides a 
starting point for getting an idea of what's going on Center-wide.
</para>

<para>
Clicking on the project title of any of the posts in the forum will
take you to the project specific forum for that project. This page
is layed out similarly to the generic forum page but only includes posts
specific to that project, log entries of developers in that project,
and the most recently modified items for that project.
</para>

<para>Log entries are developer specific. They may be used to just
quickly write down what you're working on at the moment, mention
any problems that you're encountering or to just jot down ideas
floating around your head that aren't necessarily project specific.
</para>

</chapter>

<chapter id="tips">
<title>Tips and Tricks: How to make the most of the PMT2</title>

<para>USE IT! And make sure that everyone else on your project uses it
as well. The PMT won't do much good if you don't use it to keep track
of *ALL* bugs and action items for a project. If you're having trouble
getting the other developers/managers on a project to use it, simply
stop accepting bug reports through other means and, instead of telling
them about bugs or action items through other means, just put it in
the PMT; they'll learn. If you encounter a bug and fix it before you
have a chance to put it into the PMT, it's a good idea to put in an
entry anyway (and just resolve it immediately after you enter
it). This will help document the progress of your project. Plus,
having the bug entry in there already may save you time when
(inevitably, it pops up again later on).</para>

<para>You may find it helpful to bookmark your user page and visit it
frequently. For convenience, any page in the PMT may be
bookmarked.</para>

<para>Honor the distinction between bugs and action items. The
distinction is there for a reason. Bugs should only be problems with
the product itself (site/page/program/etc); either something is there
that shouldn't be or something that should be there isn't. An action
item is a task that needs to be completed. Typically, once an action
item is completed and verified, it will be done with; bugs sometimes
exist in quasi-finished states and have the annoying habit of
reappearing when someone changes a seemingly unrelated part of the
project.</para>

<para>Feel free to create test projects to try out different features
of the PMT if you are unsure of how things work and don't want to
screw up a working project. Just delete it when you're done so it
doesn't clutter things up.</para>

<para>Use the individual logs on a regular basis. Get yourself in the
habit of spending 15 minutes at the end of each day writing a 
quick summary of what you've been up to. This little bit of self-reflection
i've found to be an amazing opportunity for personal growth. Try to 
do it every day for a month. If you keep it up, i can pretty much guarantee
that you'll conclude that it is an invaluable exercise. Furthermore,
when it comes time to write your personal self-performance review (every six months)
for full-time employees, having an archive of log entries makes it
much simpler to remember in great detail what you've actually 
accomplished.</para>

</chapter>

</book>
